Adegoke Akanbi

A Frontend Engineer with +3 years' experience helping companies and clients build elegant, scalable and reusable frontend interfaces. I fell in love with the magical powers of coding while collaborating (as a Counsel) with developers to create a digital solution. Now, I relish every moment writing code.

2492 Post Road
Unit 21, Oakville
Ontario, L6H 0K1
+1 (289) 818-3437
goke.akanbi@gmail.com
Github Profile
Portfolio Website

EXPERIENCE

78 Financial Solutions Ltd, Nigeria — Frontend Engineer

July 2021 - Present

I bridge the gap between graphic design and technical implementation by translating UI/UX design wireframes to reusable, scalable and well-commented code;

I collaborate with back-end developers to integrate UI components with APIs and databases;

I participate in code reviews and sprint meetings to ensure prompt delivery of web solutions. I also volunteered to be responsible for gathering information from end users about internal and external web applications for functionality and service improvements.

I improved accessibility of the company's internal and public facing websites by incorporating WAI-ARIA specifications in web solutions. I also enhanced the company's online visibility by implementing SEO principles on the company's websites;

I debug errors, troubleshoot issues, and perform routine performance optimizations on web applications.

Keystone Bank Ltd, Nigeria — *Lead*, *Dispute Management*

Nov 2018 - August 2022

I managed and resolved customer complaints to improve customer satisfaction and reduce adverse claims;

I negotiated a dispute on behalf of the Bank saving over 2 Billion naira in litigation claims against the Bank;

I functioned as the legal IT support and Operational Risk Officer, responding to service issues and requests in respect of the dispute and vendor management portals in a timely manner;

I provide onboarding training to new intakes to the Dispute Management Team.

SKILLS

JavaScript | jQuery | React.js |
Redux toolkit | Node.js |
MongoDB | Express.js |
Mongoose | NPM | NoSQL |
Wordpress | SQL | RESTful
API | Git | Github | Agile |
Webpack | Jest | Unit Testing |
SASS | Bootstrap | CSS3 |
HTML5

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

I was converted from Intern to Frontend Engineer within 2 months of internship with 78 Financials Ltd in recognition of my contribution to the Development Team.

I recommended dispute and vendor management systems that was implemented across all divisions in Keystone Bank to increase efficiency for all employees and reduce operational costs for the Bank.

I volunteered to serve as a member of the recruitment panel of Keystone Bank Ltd.

I mentored 5 direct reports as the Dispute Manager in

Access Bank Plc, Nigeria — Corporate Counsel

March 2013 - Nov 2018

I developed a format for the Enterprise Risk Management Committee Report for the Legal Division, highlighting the summary of reports of disputes, resolutions and learning points to the Management/Board of the Bank.

I trained Account Officers and Relationship Managers on credit/security documentations, regulatory and statutory requirements;

I reviewed the Bank's litigation portfolio and recommended matters that should be settled out of court to the Bank's Management for settlement.

EDUCATION

Scrimba.com, Norway (Remote) — Frontend Engineering

Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria — Law Degree (LLB)

SOME PROJECTS

Movie Search App — A web app helping users find details about their choice movies. Built leveraging React, TMDB API, CSS, and deployed with firebase.

link to project

Dictionary Web App — A simple multi-language installable dictionary app build with React, APIs and material UI.

link to project

Expense App — A progressive web app for tracking income and expenses. Main tech includes React, Redux, Service Workers, Cludflare.

link to project

Music Streaming App — A web app for streaming and downloading patented music. Built leveraging Wordpress, APIs, and custom CSS. link to project

Keystone Bank Ltd.

I was promoted within an appraisal year from a team member to team lead in Keystone Bank Ltd.